[Rhythmic drumming]
[有节奏的鼓声]
In Sixteen Hundred Seven
1607年
We sailed the open sea
我们航行在广阔的大海上
for glory, God, and gold
为了荣耀, 为了主, 为了金子
And the Vingiria Company
还有维吉尼亚公司
for the New World is like heaven
也为了天堂一般的新世界
And we'll all be rich and free
我们将会富有和自由
On so we have been told
就像维吉尼亚公司
By the Vingiria Company
告诉我们的那样
[Chorus humming]
[齐声哼唱]
[Background chatter]
[动物叫声]
[Baby crying]
[小孩哭声]
for glory, God, and gold
为了荣耀, 为了主, 为了金子
And the Vingiria Company
还有维吉尼亚公司
-Ready to hoist the cannon ? -Aye!
-准备好吊起加农炮了吗? -恩!
Hey, look, ls that Smith?
嗨, 看, 那是Smith吗?
That's him, all right, The old sea dog,
就是他, 没错 那个老练的水手
Captain John Smith?
John Smith船长?
l've heard some amazing stories about him,
我听说过很多关于他的惊险故事
Are you coming on this voyage, too?
你也参加这次航行吗?
Course he is, you half-wit!
显然, 你个笨蛋!
You can't fight lndians without John Smith!
没有John Smith, 你别想和印第安人打交道!
That's right,
没错
l'm not about to let you boys have all the fun,
我可不想让你们这些小孩 去独享航行的乐趣
On the beaches of Vinginny
在Virginny的海岸
Thene's diamonds like debris
有石块大的钻石
Thene's silver rivers flowing
有银子做的河流在流淌
Gold you pick night off a tnee
金子在树上采撷
With a nugget for my Winnie
一块送给我亲爱的
And another one for me
另一块留给自己
And all the rest'll go
然后剩下的全部归于
To the Vingiria Company
维吉尼亚公司
It's glory, God, and gold
这是荣耀, 这是主, 这是金子
And the Vingiria Company
也是维吉尼亚公司
[Thunder and dramatic music]
[雷声和戏剧音乐]
[Men shouting]
[男人喊声]
SAILOR: Full anchon nelease!
水手: 抛下所有的锚!
[Men grunting]
[男声咕哝]
Come on, lads! Come on!
加油, 伙计们! 加油!
Give me a hand, someone!
谁, 来帮帮我!
W atch out
当心
[Men shouting]
[男人喊声]
Faster! She's taking on more water!
快点! 更多水涌进来了!
Look out! Aah!
当心! 啊!
[Creak, snap]
[吱吱声, 绳索断开]
John! Get down here!
John! 快点过来!
The cannons are breaking loose!
加农炮挣脱下来了!
-Reef the topsails! -Aye, sir!
-把帆收起来! -是的, 先生!
Steady on your course!
稳住!
lt's all right, Thomas! We'll get her tied off,
很好, Thomas! 我们来将它绑好
Say your prayers, lads!
祈祷吧, 伙计们!
Look out! Aah!
当心! 啊!
-Oh! -No!
-哦! -不!
Thomas, watch o--
Thomas, 当心...
Help!
救命!
Man overboard!
有人落水了!
BEN: Stay youn counse! He's lost!
BEN: 待在你们自己的地方! 他已经没救了!
Help!
救命!
-Pull the pin, -Aye, sir!
-打开钩子 -是的, 先生!
BEN: Smith!
BEN: Smith!
Smith!
Smith!
Are you crazy?!
你疯了吗?!
Hang on, Thomas, l've got you!
坚持住, Thomas, 我够到你了!
Quick--the rope!
快--绳子!
Heave!
拉起来!
Come on, lads! Pull!
加油, 伙计们! 使劲拽!
Pull! Pull!
使劲! 使劲!
Put your back into it!
你们向后背着拽!
Hang on!
坚持住!
[Grunting]
[咕哝声]
There, my lucky lads!
哈, 幸运的伙计们!
[Coughs]
[咳嗽声]
Well,,,that was refreshing,
哈哈...刚才真是爽啊
Well done, Smith,
干得好, Smith
Of course,,,
当然...
you'd all do the same for me,
在我看来你们也干的不错
-Yes, yes, -Oh, sure, sure,
-是啊, 是啊 -哦, 没错, 没错
-Of course we would! -We would!
-我们当然会的! -我们会的!
Absolutely!
绝对地!
[Thunder]
[雷声]
Trouble on deck?
甲板上出了什么麻烦吗?
Governor Ratcliffe!
Ratcliffe长官!
Thomas fell overboard, sir,
Thomas掉进水里了, 长官
Thank heavens he's been successfully retrieved,
谢天谢地他又被救回来了
-Well done, Smith, -Thank you, sir,
-干得好, Smith -谢谢, 长官
Don't lose heart, men,
不要灰心, 大家
lt won't be long before we reach the New World,,,
离我们的新世界已经不远了...
and remember what awaits us there,,,
记住什么在等待着我们...
-Freedom,,, -[Arf]
-自由... -[汪]
-Prosperity,,, -[Arf arf]
-繁荣... -[汪汪]
the adventure of our lives,
我们生命的伟大历程
You're the firest crew England has to offer,,,
你们是全英国最好的船员...
and nothing-- not wind nor rain,,,
没有任何东西-- 不论是风是雨
nor a thousand bloodthirsty savages,,,
还是千百个残忍的野蛮人
shall stand in our way,
能够挡住我们的去路
Carry on, men!
坚持住, 大家!
[Cheering]
[欢呼声]
A stirring oration, sir,
一场激动人心的演说, 长官
l'm sure the men were most exhilaraaa-ted!
我肯定大家都很受鼓舞!
Let us hope so,
希望是这样
l'll need those witless peasants to dig up my gold, won't l?
我需要那班乡巴佬去 帮我挖金子, 不是吗?
[Growls]
[低声咆哮]
This New World's going to be great, John,
新世界一定棒极了, John
l'm going to get a pile of gold,,,
我要去弄一大堆金子...
build me a big house,,,
盖座大大的房子...
and if any lndian tries to stop me, l'll blast him,
如果哪个印第安人敢阻止我 我就开枪打死他
You just worry about that fortune of yours, Thomas,
你只管关心你的金子好了, Thomas
Leave the savages to me,
那些野蛮人交给我
You think they'll give us much trouble?
你觉得他们会给我们 制造很多麻烦吗?
Not as much trouble as Smith'll give them,
Smith会给他们更多
CREW:  We'll kill ounselves an injun
船员:  我们会为自己 除去一个印第安人
JOHN: On maybe two on thnee
JOHN: 或者可能两个三个
We'ne stalwant men and bold of the
我们是坚定勇敢的
Vingiria Company
维吉尼亚公司人
THOMAS: What do you suppose the New World will look like?
THOMAS: 你们觉得新世界 将会是怎样的?
JOHN: Like all the others, l suppose,
JOHN: 就像其它的一样 我觉得
l've seen hundreds of New Worlds, Thomas,
我见过几百个新世界, Thomas
What could possibly be different about this one?
这个可能会有什么区别吗?
CREW: It's glory, God, and gold
船员: 这是荣耀, 这是主, 这是金子
And the Vingiria Company
也是维吉尼亚公司
Hega hega
嗨咯 嗨咯
Ya-hi-ye hega
呀-嗨-耶 嗨咯
Ya-hi-ye-ne-he
呀-嗨-耶-呐-哈
Hega
嗨咯
[Blows horn]
[号角声]
Hega, hega
嗨咯 嗨咯
Ya-hi-ye hega
呀-嗨-耶 嗨咯
Ya-hi-ye-ne-he
呀-嗨-耶-呐-哈
Hega
嗨咯
[Blows horn]
[号角声]
Steady as the beating dnum
规律得像打鼓
Singing to the cedan flute
唱歌像松笛
Seasons go and seasons come
四季交替
Bning the conn and bean the fnuit
带来玉米 结出水果
By the watens sweet and clean
清甜透明的水
Whene the mighty stungeon is
养育着有力的鲟鱼
Plant the squash and neap the bean
种下南瓜 灌溉大豆
All the earth oun Mother gives
每一寸土地都是母亲所赐
O, Gneat Spinit, hean our song
哦, 情绪高涨 听我们唱歌
Help us keep the ancient ways
沿袭着古老的传统
Keep the sacned fines stnong
维持着神圣的火焰
Walk in balance all our days
一切都已进入我们和谐的生活
Seasons go and seasons come
四季交替
Steady as the beating dnum
规律得就像打鼓
Plum to seed to bud to plum
从李子到种子到芽再到李子
Hega hega
嗨咯 嗨咯
Ya-hi-ye hega
呀-嗨-耶 嗨咯
Steady as the beating dnum
规律得像打鼓
Hega hega
嗨咯 嗨咯
Ya-hi-ye-ne-he hega
呀-嗨-耶-呐-哈 嗨咯
Ya-hi-ye hega
呀-嗨-耶 嗨咯
Hey! Unh!
嗨! 恩!
Hega hega
嗨咯 嗨咯
[Speaking Algonquian]
[用阿尔冈琴语说]
lt's good to be home,
回家太好了
The Masawomecs are defeated!
Masawomecs部落被我们击败了!
With the help of our brothers,,,
在我们兄弟的帮助下...
our villages are safe again,
我们的部落又安全了
[Cheering]
[欢呼声]
Your return has brought much joy to the village,
你的回来已经为我们的部落 带来很大的愉快了
Look at all the smiling faces,
看看这些笑脸
Yes, But there's one smiling face l don't see,
恩, 但是还有 一张笑脸我没有看到
Where is my daughter?
我的宝贝女儿呢?
You know Pocahontas,
你知道Pocahontas
She has her mother's spirit,
她有着她母亲的热情
She goes wherever the wind takes her,
风会将她带到任何地方
[Gentle winds blowing]
[温柔的风吹着]
NAKOMA: Pocahontas!
NAKOMA: Pocahontas!
Your father's back,
你父亲回来了
Come down here!
下到这儿来!
He's back, Flit,
他回来了, Flit
[Chitters]
[啾啾声]
[Squeaking]
[啸叫声]
Come on, Meeko!
跟上, Meeko!
No! Not that,,,way,
不! 不是那条...路
Show off,
卖弄
Tch, tch, tch,
啧, 啧, 啧
Rrrr!
喏!
[Squeaks]
[尖叫声]
[Squeaking]
[啸叫声]
Pocahontas?
Pocahontas?
Are you all right?
你还好吗?
You'd better be all right,,,
你最好没事...
because l'm not coming in after you--
因为我不是你的跟班--
[Cough cough]
[咳咳]
Don't you think we're getting,,,
你不觉得我们玩这种游戏...
a little old for these games?
似乎有些老了吗?
[Laughing]
[笑声]
[Coughing]
[咳嗽声]
[Chittering]
[滑]
[Squeaks]
[尖叫声]
[Boing]
[啵]
POCAHONTAS: Help me tunn this thing oven:
POCAHONTAS: 帮我把船翻过来
What were you doing up there?
你在那上面做什么?
Thinking, Meeko!
你猜, Meeko!
About the dream again? Have you figured it out yet?
又是关于那个梦? 你还没有完全想出来吗?
l know it means something,
我知道那一定暗示着什么东西
l just don't know what,
但就是不知道具体是什么
You should ask your father about it,
你应该向你父亲问问这件事
Maybe l should,
可能是的
Come on, Flit,
上来, Flit
Quit playing arourd, We have to get back,
不要再到处乱玩 我们得回去了
[Squeak]
[尖叫声]
POWHATAN: :::faced a detenmined enemy:
POWHATAN: ...面对着一个坚定的敌人
The battle lasted fnom the nising of the sun:::
战斗从太阳刚刚升起
until the evening shadow fell,
一直持续到夜幕降临
Our warriors fought with courage,,,
我们的战士勇往直前
but none as bravely as Kocoum,,,
但是还没人像Kocoum这般勇敢...
for he attacked with the fierce strength of the bear,
因为他战斗像熊一样的凶猛
He has pnoven himself to be:::
他的实际行动证明了他就是...
-He is so handsome! -l especially love the smile,
-他可真帅啊! -我特别喜欢他的微笑
POWHATAN: :::destnoying eveny enemy in his path:
POWHATAN: ...用他的方式来消灭每一个敌人
Tonight, we will feast in his honor,
今晚, 我们要为他举行盛宴
[Whooping]
[欢呼声]
-My daughter, -Wingapo, Father,
-宝贝女儿 -一切安好, 父亲
Seeing you gives me great joy,
见到你就是我最大的快乐
l'm so glad you've come home safely,
真高兴您平安回家
Come with me, We have much to talk about,
跟我来 我有太多话要对你说
l want to hear everything you have been doing,
我要听听你做的每一件事情
[Chirping]
[叽叽喳喳声]
Father, for many nights now,,,
父亲, 好几个晚上...
l've been having a very strange dream,
我都做到同一个奇怪的梦
l think it's telling me something's about to happen,,,
我想那是要告诉我 什么事将要发生
something exciting,
一件激动人心的事
Yes, Something exciting is about to happen,
没错, 是有一件激动人心的事即将发生
Really? What is it?
真的吗? 那是什么?
Kocoum has asked to seek your hand in marriage,
Kocoum已经向我提亲 他要和你结婚
Marry Kocoum?
嫁给Kocoum?
[Chitters]
[啾啾声]
Paah!
啪!
l told him it would make my heart soar,
我告诉他那会让我心情飞扬
But he's so,,,serious,
但是, 他太... 严肃了
My daughter, Kocoum will make a fine husband,
我的女儿 Kocoum将会是一个好丈夫
He is loyal and stnong and will build you:::
他既忠诚又强壮 会用结实的墙壁为你建造...
a good house with stundy walls:
一所好房子
With him, you will be safe fnom hanm:
和他在一起 你会很安全
Father, l think my dream is pointing me down another path,
父亲, 我想我的梦 正在指引我走向另一条路
This is the right path for you,
这对你来说是一条正确的路
But why can't l choose--Oh!
但是为什么我就没有选择的... 哦!
[Hiccup]
[打嗝]
[Laughs]
[笑声]
Pocahontas, come with me,
Pocahontas, 跟我来
You are the daughter of the chief,
你是酋长的女儿
lt is time to take your place among our people,
是该你履行责任的时候了
Even the wild mountain stream,,,
即使山野小溪...
must some day join the big river,
有一天也会流进大河
As the niven cuts his path
当大河截断他的路
Though the niven's pnoud and stnong
虽然大河骄傲和强壮
He will choose the smoothest course
他也会选择一段最平坦的路程
That's why rivers live so long,
这就是为什么 大河能活得那么久
They'ne steady
他们那么稳定
As the steady beating dnum
稳定得就像打鼓
Your mother wore this for our wedding,
你母亲在我们的婚礼上戴着这个
lt was her dream to see you wear it at your own,
看见你亲手戴上是她的梦想
lt suits you,
它很配你
He wants me to be steady,
他想让我稳定
Like the river,
就像大河一样
[Meeko screeches]
[Meeko 尖叫]
But it's not steady at all,
但是他根本就不稳定
What I love most about rivers is
我之所以喜欢大河是因为
You can't step in the same niven twice
你没办法两次走进同一条河
The waten's always changing
河水始终在不停地变化
Always flowing
不断地流动
But people, I guess, can't live like that
但是人, 我猜 不能那样活着
We all must pay a pnice
我们都必须付出代价
To be safe, we lose our chance of even knowing
为了安全 我们甚至失去了去了解
What's anound the niven bend
河湾附近的景色的机会
Waiting just around the niven bend?
就在河湾附近等待?
I look once mone
让我再看一次
Just around the niven bend
就在河湾附近
Beyond the shone
超越了海岸
Whene the gulls fly free
那里有海鸥自由飞翔
Don't know what for
不知道为了什么
What I dneam the day might send
我梦到的那天可能会到来
Just around the niven bend
就在河湾附近
for me
为了我
Coming for me
为我而来
I feel it thene beyond those tnees
我感觉到它就在那儿 树的那边
And night behind these watenfalls
夜在这些水帘背后
Eek eek eek!
哎 哎 哎!
Can I ignone that sound of distant dnumming
我能忽视远处的鼓声吗
for a handsome, stundy husband
(鼓声)为了一个英俊可靠的丈夫
Who builds handsome, stundy walls
他将为我建造漂亮结实的墙壁
And never dneams that something might be coming
然后再也不去想有事将要发生
Just around the niven bend?
就在河湾附近?
Just around the niven bend
就在河湾附近
I look once mone
让我再看一次
Beyond the shone
超越了海岸
Somewhene past the sea
那里就是大海
Don't know what for
不知道为了什么
Why do all my dneams extend
为什么我的梦总是那么超前
Just around the niven bend?
就在河湾附近?
Just around the niven bend
就在河湾附近
Should I choose the smoothest counse
我是不是应该选择最平滑的路程
Steady as the beating dnum?
稳定得就像打鼓一样?
Should I manny Kocoum?
我是不是应该嫁给Kocoum?
Is all my dneaming at an end?
我的所有梦都了解了?
On do you still
或者你还在
Wait for me, dneam given?
等着我, 拖梦人?
Just around the niven
就在河湾
Bend?
附近?
[Chitters]
[啾啾声]
GRANDMO THER WILLOW: Is that my Pocahontas?
WILLOW奶奶: 是我的Pocahontas吗?
Grandmother Willow, l need to talk to you,
Willow奶奶 我有话对你说
Good morning, child,
早上好, 孩子
l was hoping you'd visit today,
我知道你今天会来
Oh! Your mother's necklace!
哦! 你母亲的项链!
That's what l wanted to talk to you about,
这就是我打算和你说的
My father wants me to marry Kocoum,
我父亲想把我嫁给Kocoum
Kocoum? But he's so serious!
Kocoum? 但是他太严肃了!
l know, My father thinks it's the right path for me,
我知道, 我父亲 认为这是我应该走的路
But lately, l've been having this dream, and l think it's--
但是最近, 我总 在做一个梦, 我想它--
Oh, a dream! Let's hear all about it!
哦, 一个梦! 让我们来听听!
[Chittering, tweeting]
[小动物叫声]
Quiet! Phew!
安静! 哟!
Quiet!
安静!
[Ribbit]
[咕咕]
[Gulps]
[吞咽声]
Now, child, you were saying?
现在, 孩子, 你开始说吧
Well, l'm running through the woods,,,
恩, 我在树林里跑...
and then right there in front of me is an arrow,
就在我前方出现了一个箭头
As l look at it, it starts to spin,
当我去看时 它就开始旋转
A spinning arrow? How unusual!
旋转的箭头? 真不寻常!
Yes, it spins faster and faster and faster,,,
是的, 它旋转得 越来越快, 越来越快
until suddenly--it stops,
直到突然间--停止了
Hmm, Well, it seems to me this spinning arrow,,,
, 恩 看起来这个旋转的箭头...
is pointing you down your path,
正在指示你应该走的路
But, Grandmother Willow, what is my path?
但是, Willow奶奶 我的路到底在哪?
How am l ever going to find it?
我该怎样去找到它?
Ha ha! Your mother asked me the very same question,
哈哈! 你母亲问了我同样一个问题
She did? What did you tell her?
她也问了? 那你怎么回答她的?
l told her to listen,
我让她去聆听
All around you are spirits, child,
你周围都是生灵, 孩子
They live in the earth, the water, the sky,
它们生活在泥土里 水里, 天上
lf you listen, they will guide you,
如果你仔细去聆听 它们会指引你的
CHORUS, UNDER WIND: Ay ay ay ya
合唱, 在风中: 哎 哎 哎 哎
l hear the wind,
我听到风了
GRANDMO THER WILLOW: Yes: What is it telling you ?
WILLOW奶奶: 恩 它告诉你什么?
l don't understand,
我不懂
Que que na-to-na
哙 哙 呐-特-呐
You will undenstand
你会明白的
Listen with your heant
用心去聆听
Let it bneak upon you
让它来指引你
Like a wave upon the sand
就像波浪打在沙滩上
lt's saying something's coming,
它说什么东西来了
Strange clouds,,,
奇怪的云彩...
Listen with your heant
用心去聆听
You will undenstand
你会明白的
[Screeches]
[尖叫声]
[Chitters]
[啾啾声]
What do you see?
你看到了什么?
Clouds,
云彩
Stnange clouds:
奇怪的云彩
RATCLIFFE: Look at it, Wiggins:::
RATCLIFFE: 看看这儿, Wiggins...
an entine New World chock full of gold:::
一个堆满金子的新世界...
just waiting for me,
正等着我
And scores of adventures waiting for us, right, Percy?
还有许多惊险在等着我们 对吗, Percy?
Do you think we'll meet some savages?
你觉得我们会遇到那些野蛮人吗?
lf we do, we shall be sure to give them,,,
如果遇上了 我们肯定会给他们...
a proper English greeting,
一个合适的英国式问候
Oh! Gift baskets!
哦! 礼品篮!
Hmph! And he came so highly recommended,
哼! 他们被抬举得太高了
JOHN: It's penfect, Govennon:
JOHN: 一切太完美了, 长官
The water's deep enough, We can pull right up to shore,
水足够深 我们可以直接把船拖到岸边
Hey, there, Percy,
嗨, 恩, Percy
[Growls]
[低声吼]
Very well then, Give the order,
非常好 准许
Already done, sir,
已经完成, 长官
l've got a crew assembled, and they're ready to go,
我已经把船员集合好了 他们正准备出发
About the natives,,,
至于那些土著...
l'm counting on you to make sure,,,
我希望你确定一下...
those filthy heathens don't disrupt our mission,
那些肮脏的野蛮人 不要打扰我们的工作
lf they're anything like the savages l've fought before,
如果他们是我曾经 对付过的那种野蛮人
it's nothing l can't handle,
没有我不能处理的
Right, That'll be all, Smith, There's a good man,
好, 那就行了, Smith 你是个优秀的家伙
See ya, Percy,
再见, Percy
[Grrr]
[低声怒吼]
The men like Smith, don't they?
那些人喜欢Smith, 是不是?
[Growls]
[低声吼]
l've never been a,,,popular man,
我从来都不是...一个平凡的人
l like you,
我喜欢你
And don't think l don't know,,,
不要以为我不知道...
what those back-stabbers at court say about me,
那些混蛋在宫廷里是怎么说我的
Oh, yes, all that talk about being,,,
哦, 是啊, 整场对话关于一个
a pathetic social climber who's failed at everything--
可怜的想进入上流社会的人 在每一件事上总是失败--
l'm well aware that this is my last chance for glory,
我很清楚地知道这是我 最后一次为荣誉而战的机会
But mark my words, Wiggins--
你记住今天我所说的, Wiggins--
when King James sees the gold these peasants unearth,,,
当詹姆士国王看到 那些村夫挖来的金子...
success will be mine at last,
成功最终会是我的
BEN: Wake up! Shake a leg!
BEN: 醒醒! 快走!
lt's incredible,
真是难以置信
And it's all ours,
这些全都是我们的啦
l've never seen anything like it,
我从来没有见过这样的东西
lt can look like Ratcliffe's knickers, for all l care,,,
它看起来就像Ratcliffe的灯笼裤 我现在所关心的...
just as long as l get off this stinking boat!
只是尽快离开这艘发臭的烂船
Come on, men,
跟上来, 伙计们
We didn't come all this way just to look at it,
让我们去四处看看
[Birds calling]
[鸟鸣]
[Owl hoots]
[猫头鹰叫声]
[Scrapes]
[摩擦声]
BEN: Keep it taut, lads: Keep it taut! Steady!
BEN: 拉紧, 伙计们 拉紧! 牢牢地!
All right now--tie her off!
好啦--将她绑好!
Here, John, tie off this end,
这儿, John 系牢这一端
John? John?
John? John?
THOMAS: What ane you doing up thene?
THOMAS: 你在那上面干什么呢?
Getting a better look,
找一个更好的视野
[Chirps]
[叽叽喳喳声]
[Gasps]
[吸气声]
[Chittering]
[啾啾]
[Screeches]
[尖叫声]
[Pop]
[啵]
Hey!
嗨!
[Chirps]
[叽叽喳喳声]
[Gasps]
[吸气声]
Well,,,you're a strange-looking fellow,
哈...你看起来很奇怪
You hungry?
你饿了吗?
Here you go, lt's a biscuit,
拿去 这是饼干
lt's food, Well, sort of,
这是食物, 恩, 有好几种
You like it, eh?
你喜欢, 恩?
Try eating it for four months straight,
试着连续吃上四个月
You got a friend back there?
那后面有你的朋友?
Hey--what the--what-- Ha ha! Watch out,
嗨--什么--这是什么-- 哈哈! 当心
[Bugle blows in distance]
[远处喇叭声响起]
No--Get that--Look out!
不--别这样--当心!
John, you better get down here!
John, 你最好还是下来!
The governor's coming ashore,
长官过来了
All right, All right, l'm leaving,
好, 好 我这就走了
[Squeaks]
[尖叫声]
[Overlapping chatter]
[啾啾地交谈]
MAN: They have hain on thein faces like dogs:
人们: 他们像狗一样脸上长毛
My brothers, we must know more about these visitors,
兄弟们, 我们必须 仔细了解一下这些来客
Kekata, what do you see?
Kekata, 你怎么看?
[Chanting]
[念咒语]
[Speaking Algonquian]
[用阿尔冈琴语说]
These are not men like us,,,
他们并不是像我们这样的人...
but strange beasts with bodies that shine like the sun,,,
而是有着能够像太阳 一样发光的躯体的怪物...
and weapons that spout fire and thunder,
他们有着能够喷射火和雷的武器
They pnowl the earth like navenous wolves:::
他们巡游着土地 就像贪婪的恶狼...
consuming evenything in thein path:
用他们的方式来毁灭一切
[Baby cries]
[小孩哭声]
Great Powhatan, l will lead our warriors,,,
Great Powhatan 我要带领我们的战士们
to the river and attack,
去河边去战斗
We will destroy these invaders,,,
我们要摧毁这些侵略者...
the way we destroyed the Masawomecs,
就像我们摧毁Masawomecs部落那样
Kocoum, in that battle we knew how to fight our enemy,,,
Kocoum, 在那场战役中 我们知道如何和敌人作战...
but these pale visitors are strange to us,
但是这些白人我们并不了解
Take some men to the river to observe them,
带一些人去河边监视他们
Let us hope they do not intend to stay,
希望他们不要准备在这儿逗留
l hereby claim this land and all its riches,,,
我这里宣布这块土地 还有这里所有的财富...
in the name of His Majesty, King James l,,,
以最高权威詹姆士国王的名义...
and do so name this settlement Jamestown,
命名为詹姆斯敦
[Men cheering]
[欢呼声]
Bravo! Bravo! Beautifully spoken, sir!
哦也! 哦也! 精彩的演说, 长官!
Hurry now, Percy,
快点, Percy
We must be all squeaky clean for the New World,
我们得为新世界而尽快清洗干净
[Chittering]
[啾啾声]
[Splash]
[泡沫四溅]
[Growling]
[低声怒吼]
[Ruff ruff ruff]
[汪汪汪]
[Splat]
[啪]
Captain Smith,,,
Smith船长...
it appears l've selected the perfect location, eh?
看来我选择了一个 完美的露营地, 恩?
Not a savage in sight,
没有看到一个野蛮人
Just because we don't see them,,,
只是我们还没有看到他们...
doesn't mean they're not out there, sir,
并不代表他们不在, 长官
Well, then perhaps you should venture forth,,,
好, 那么也许你应该 向前去观察一下...
and determine their whereabouts, hmm?
弄清楚他们的行踪, ?
lf there are any lndians out there, l'll find them,
如果这儿有印第安人的话 我会发现他们的
Now, gentlemen, to work,
现在, 大家, 开始干活
You men, get the ship unloaded,
你们这些人 去把船上的东西卸下来
You men build the fort,
你们去建造堡垒
The rest of you,,, break out the shovels!
其他的... 拿出你们的铲子来!
lt's time to start digging!
可以开挖了!
BOTH: Digging?
两个人同时: 挖?
Of course!
当然!
Let's not forget what the Spanish found,,,
不要忘记那些 西班牙人发现了什么...
when they came to the New World,
在他们来到新世界之后
Gold! Mountains of it,
金子! 满山的金子
Why, for years, they've been ravaging the New World,,,
啊, 没几年 他们就将新世界掠夺一空...
of its most precious resources,
拿走了所有的宝贵资源
But now,,,
但是现在...
it's our turn,
该轮到我们了
The gold of Contez
金子做的Contez
The jewels of Pizanno
珠宝镶嵌的Pizarro
Will seem like mene tninkets
看起来就会是小玩意
By this time tomonnow
在明天这个时候
The gold we find hene
我们在这儿找到的金子
Will dwanf them by fan
将会让它们不值一提
Oh, with all ya got in ya, boys
哦, 使出全力, 孩子们
Dig up Vingiria, boys
开垦维吉尼亚, 孩子们
Mine, boys
我的, 孩子们
Mine eveny mountain
我的, 每一座山脉
And dig, boys
挖吧, 孩子们
Dig till ya dnop
挖吧直到最后一点
Gnab a pick, boys
拿走精美的, 孩子们
Quick, boys
快, 孩子们
Shove in a shovel
推进你的铲子
Uncoven those lovely pebbles
去挖掘那些可爱的小石头
That spankle and shine
它们闪闪发光
It's gold
它们就是金子
And it's mine
它们是我的
Mine
我的
[Gunshot]
[枪响]
MEN:  Dig and diggety dig
人们:  挖啊, 努力地挖
And dig and dig and diggety dig
挖啊, 挖, 努力地挖
Hey, nonny nonny, hi, nonny nonny
嗨, 哝呢哝呢
Ooh, how I love it
哦, 我真是爱死它了
Riches for cheap
轻而易举得来的财富
Hey, nonny, nonny, hi, nonny, nonny
嗨, 哝呢哝呢
Thene'll be heaps of it
这儿会有很多很多
And I'll be on top of the heap
我就站在它的顶端
Diggety dig
努力地挖
My nivals back home
我的敌人都见鬼去吧
It's not that I'm bitten
并不是我怀恨
But think how they'll squinm
只要想想他们怎样地忸怩
When they see how I glitten
当看到我闪闪发光
The ladies at count
宫廷里的女士们
Will be all a-twitten
心里将会紧张不已
The king will newand me
国王将会奖赏我
He'll knight me--No!
他会授予我爵位--不!
Lond me
让位给我
It's mine!
这是我的!
Mine, mine for the taking
我的, 我的 为了憧憬的未来
It's mine, boys, mine me that gold!
这是我的, 孩子们 我的那些金子!
With those nuggets dug, it's
把那些金块挖出来 它是
glory they'll give me
我将被授予荣耀
My dean fniend King Jimmy
我亲爱的朋友詹姆士国王
Will pnobably build me a shnine
将会给我建造一座圣殿
When all of the gold
在所有这些金子
Is mine
都是我的之后
And dig and dig and diggety dig
挖啊, 挖, 努力地挖
All of my life
我一生所追求的
I have seanched for a land like this one
就是这样一块土地
A wild on mone challenging countny
一个狂野刺激的国度
I couldn't design
我没法设计
Hundreds of dangens await
许多危险在等待
And I don't plan to miss one
我不会错过任何一个
In a land I can claim
在一片我可以认领的土地
A land I can tame
一片我可以驯服的土地
The gneatest adventune is mine
最伟大的历险是我的
Keep on wonking, lads
努力工作, 伙计们
Don't be shinking, lads
不要偷懒, 伙计们
Mine, boys
我的, 孩子们
Mine
我的
Mine me that
我的那些
- Gold - Dig, dig
- 金子 - 挖啊, 挖
And diggety
努力地挖
- Beautiful gold - Dig
- 美丽的金子 - 挖啊
for that gold
为了那些金子
This is my land, my land
这是我的领地, 我的领地
Make the mounds big, boys
让土堆变得更大, 孩子们
I'd help you to dig, boys
我也想帮你们挖, 孩子们
But I've got this cnick in me spine
但是我肌肉抽搐
This land we behold
我们看到的这片土地
This beauty untold
美丽得无法形容
A man can be bold
人可以勇敢
It all can be sold
这些都可以拿来卖
And the gold
这些金子
Is
是
Mine
我的
- Mine - Dig, dig
- 我的 - 挖啊, 挖
And diggety dig
努力地挖
Hey, nonny, nonny, it's mine
嗨, 哝呢哝呢 这是我的
[Birds chirping]
[鸟鸣]
[Rustling]
[沙沙声]
No! Wait! Please,,,
不! 等等! 请不要走...
JOHN: Please!
JOHN: 不要走!
Don't run off,
不要跑开
lt's all right,
没事
l'm not going to hurt you,
我不会伤害你的
Here, Let me help you out of there,
恩, 让我扶你上来
[Speaking Algonquian]
[用阿尔冈琴语说]
You don't understand a word l'm saying, do you?
你听不懂我所说的, 是吗?
lt's all right,
没关系
[Gentle winds blowing]
[微风拂过]
GRANDMO THER WILLOW: Listen with your heant
WILLOW奶奶: 用心去聆听
You will undenstand
你会明白的
[Squeaking]
[啸叫]
Let it bneak upon you
让它来指引你
Like a wave upon the sand
就像波浪打在沙滩上
Who are you?
你是谁?
Listen with your heant
用心去聆听
You will undenstand
你会明白的
Pocahontas,
Pocahontas
What? What did you say?
什么? 你刚才说什么?
My name is Pocahontas,
我的名字叫Pocahontas
l'm John Smith,
我是John Smith
RATCLlFFE: That's it, Keep at it, men,
RATCLlFFE: 就在这儿, 继续挖, 大家
Keep digging, lt's gotta be here somewhere,
继续挖啊 一定就在这儿某个地方
[Bird call]
[鸟鸣]
There's 30 more of them down by the ridge,
下面山脊上他们有30多个人
That makes more than a hundred!
就是说总共有百来个人!
Anything yet?
找到什么了吗?
Nothing but rocks and dirt, sir,
除了石头和泥土 什么都没有, 长官
How long are we going to keep digging like this, sir?
我们到底还要挖多久, 长官?
Aye! We're slaving away, busting our backs day and night,
对阿! 我们整天整夜没完没了地挖
For king and country, l know, l know,
为了国王, 为了国家 我明白, 我明白
And l'm sure you're fatigued,
我知道你们很疲倦
Wiggins!
Wiggins!
RATCLIFFE: Wiggins!
RATCLIFFE: Wiggins!
Coming!
来啦!
Dispose of this,
处理掉这个
Who's a good doggie?
谁是好狗狗?
Hmm?
?
Fetch, boy!
接住, 乖孩子!
[Yelps]
[汪汪汪]
Savages! lt's an ambush! Arm yourselves!
水手们! 有埋伏! 武装起来!
Run!
跑!
Make sure every man has a musket!
每个人都带上一把步枪!
Shoot!
射击!
Them, you idiot!
他们, 你个笨蛋!
Where's that blasted Smith when l need him?
那个该死的Smith去哪儿了? 我正需要他
Namontac!
Namontac!
Back to the village!
快回部落去!
[Cheering]
[欢呼声]
Shut up, Shut up, you fools!
闭嘴 闭嘴, 你们这些笨蛋!
They'll be back,
他们会回来的
[Gasps]
[吸气声]
Everyone back to camp,
所有人都回营地去
Get the rest of the cannons ashore,,,
把所有加农炮都弄上岸来
and finish building the fort!
立刻完成堡垒的修建工作!
Aye, Governor!
是的, 长官!
And you,,,
还有你...
learn to use that thing properly,
好好学学怎么用那个玩意吧
A man's not a man unless he knows how to shoot,
不会玩枪就不是男人
[Kekata chanting]
[Kekata念咒语]
These beasts invade our shores,,,
那些怪物侵入了我们的海岸...
and now this,
然后现在又...
This wound is strange to me,
这个伤口对我来说太奇怪了
[Groans]
[呻吟声]
We will fight this enemy,,,
我们要和这些敌人战斗...
but we cannot do it alone,
但是我们不能独自去做
Kocoum, send messengers to every village in our nation,
Kocoum, 送信给我们的每一个部落
We will call on our brothers to help us fight,
我们要召集我们的 兄弟们一起去战斗
These white men are dangerous!
这些白人非常危险!
No one is to go near them,
任何人都不许接近他们
JOHN: It's called a helmet:
JOHN: 这个叫做头盔
Helmet,
头盔
[Tap tap] [Screech]
[叮叮] [尖叫声]
So,,,what river is this?
恩...这是什么河啊?
Quyukhanic,
Quyukhanic河
You have the most unusual names here,
你有着这儿最不同寻常的名字
Chicahomeni, Quyu,,,Quyukhanic,
Chicahomeni Quyu...Quyukhanic河
Pocahontas,
Pocahontas
You have the most unusual name, too,
你同样有着最不同寻常的名字
John Smith,
John Smith
Hey!
嗨!
ls this bottomless pit a friend of yours?
这个永不知足的 小家伙是你的朋友吗?
Meeko!
Meeko!
How do you do, Meeko?
你好, Meeko?
lt's all right, lt's just a handshake,
没什么 这只是一个握手罢了
Here, let me show you,
恩, 让我来教你
Nothing's happening,
不会发生什么吧
No, no, l need your hand first,
不, 不 我只要你伸出手来
lt's how we say hello,
这是问好的方式
[Squeaks]
[尖叫声]
This is how we say hello, Wingapo,
这是我们问好的方式 Wingapo
And how we say good-bye,,,Ah-nah,
然后这是我们怎样说再见...Ah-nah
l like hello better,
我更喜欢问好
[Squeaks]
[尖叫声]
Yeah, l remember you,
对了, 我记得你
Flit just doesn't like strangers,
Flit只是不喜欢陌生人
But l'm not a stranger anymore,
但是我已经不是陌生人了
Stubborn little fellow, isn't he?
顽固的小家伙 是不是?
-Pbbt! -Very stubborn,
-MM! -确实有些
Hey!
嗨!
Meeko! Come back here,
Meeko! 回到这儿来
Don't worry, He can't hurt it,
别当心, 他弄不坏的
Hey! What are you doing?
嗨! 你在干什么?
Meeko, bring that back,
Meeko, 把它拿回来
No, it's all right, He can keep it,
不, 就这样好了 他会保管好的
Call it a gift,
就当作见面礼吧
[Banging]
[]
What was that?
那是什么?
-My compass, -Compass?
-我的指南针 -指南针?
lt tells you how to find your way when you get lost,
当你迷路的时候 它会告诉你怎么走
But it's all right, l'll get another one in London,
但是没事 回到伦敦我会买一个新的
London? ls that your village?
伦敦? 那是你的部落吗?
Yes, lt's a very big village,
是的, 一个非常大的部落
What's it like?
那是怎样的?
Well, it's got streets filled with carriages,,,
恩, 那儿有车来车往的街道...
bridges over the rivers,,,
跨越河流的大桥...
and buildings as tall as trees,
还有树一般高的建筑
l'd like to see those things,
我想去看看那些东西
-You will, -How?
-你会的 -怎样?
We're going to build them here,
我们将在这儿建造那些东西
We'll show your people how to use this land properly,,,
我们会教你们的人 怎样合理利用土地
how to make the most of it,
怎样最好地利用它
Make the most of it?
最好地利用它?
Yes, We'll build roads and decent houses--
对, 我们会修建 公路和漂亮的房屋--
Our houses are fine,
我们的房子也很好
You think that only because you don't know any better,
你那样想只是因为 你不知道更好的
Wait a minute, Don't take it that--
等等 不要那么--
Hey--hey! Wait!
嗨--嗨! 等等!
[Squeak squeak squeak]
[尖叫 尖叫 尖叫]
Wait! There's so much we can teach you,
等等! 我们还能教你们更多
We've improved the lives of savages all over the world,
我们要改变 全世界的野蛮的生活
Savages?!
野蛮的?!
Not that you're a savage,
倒不是你野蛮
-Just my people, -No,
-那就是我们的人民 -不
Listen, that's not what l meant,
听着, 那不是我想说的
-Let me explain, -Let go!
-让我来解释 -让我走!
No, l'm not letting you leave,
不, 我不会让你离开的
Look, don't do this,
恩, 不要那样子
Savage is just a word, you know?
野蛮仅仅是一个词而已, 你明白吗?
A term for,,, people who are uncivilized,
一个术语... 来形容那些未开化的人
Like me,
就像我
Well, when l say uncivilized,,,
恩, 我说的未开化...
what l mean is--is--
是指--指--
Whoa--uh-aah--uh!
哦--恩-啊--恩!
Oof!
哦呋!
[Clang]
[当]
What you mean is,,,not like you,
你是指...不和你一样
You think I'm an ignonant savage
你觉得我是一个无知的野蛮人
And you've been so many places
你去过那么多地方
I guess it must be so
我想那应该是这样
But still, I cannot see
但是仍然, 我不明白
If the savage one is me
如果野蛮人都是我
How can thene be so much
怎么还会有那么多的东西
That you don't know?
你不知道?
You don't know
你不知道
[Music playing]
[音乐继续]
You think you own whateven land you land on
你认为你所登陆的 土地都是你的
The earth is just a dead thing you can claim
大地只是一个没有生命的东西
But I know eveny nock and tnee and cneatune
但是我知道每一块石头 每一棵树木每一个生灵
Has a life, has a spinit
都有它的生命 有它的灵魂
Has a name
有它的名字
You think the only people who ane people
你认为只有像你那样
Ane the people who look and think like you
看问题和想问题的人 才是真正的人
But if you walk the footsteps of a stnangen
但是如果你沿着一个 陌生人的足迹走下去
You'll leann things
你会学到
You never knew you never knew
你从来不知道的事情
Have you even heand the wolf cny
你曾经听到过野狼嚎叫
To the blue conn moon
对着蓝色天空里的明月
On ask the gninning bobcat why he gninned?
或者问过野猫 为什么它要呲牙咆哮吗?
Can you sing with all the voices
你能和着大山的声音
Of the mountain ?
一起唱歌吗?
Can you paint with all the colons
你能用风的颜色
Of the wind?
来绘画吗?
Come nun the hidden pine tnails
来沿着寂寞的林间小路
Of the forest
奔跑
Come taste the sun-sweet bennies
来尝尝大地
Of the earth
甜美的浆果
Come noll in all the riches all around you
来在你周围 富饶的土地上打滚
And for once, never wonden what they're worth
只是, 不要去计较是否值得
The nainstonm and the niven
暴风雨和河流
Ane my brothers
是我的兄弟
The henon and the otten
苍鹭和水獭
Ane my fniends
是我的朋友
And we ane all connected to each other
我们彼此都息息相关
In a cincle in a hoop that never ends
周而复始永不停息
How high
枫树
Does the sycamone grow?
长得多么的高?
If you cut it down
如果你把它砍了
Then you'll never know
你将永远不会知道
And you'll
你将永远
Never hean the wolf cny
不会听到野狼嚎叫
To the blue conn moon
对着蓝色天空里的明月
for whethen we ane white on coppen-skinned
不管我们是白色 还是棕色的皮肤
We need to sing with all the voices
我们需要和着
Of the mountain
大山的声音来歌唱
We need to paint with all the colons
我们需要用
Of the wind
风的颜色来绘画
You can own the earth, and still
你会拥有大地 仍然
All you'll own is earth until
所有你将拥有的是大地直到
You can paint
你能够
With all the colons
用风的颜色
Of the wind
来绘画
[Distant drumbeat]
[远处鼓声]
What is it?
这是什么?
The drums, They mean trouble,
鼓声 它意味着麻烦
l shouldn't be here,
我不能再待在这儿了
-l want to see you again, -l can't,
-我想再见到你 -我不能
-Please, don't leave, -l'm sorry,
-求你, 不要离开 -我很抱歉
l have to go,
我必须得走了
[Thunder rolls]
[雷声]
BEN: All night! This one's neady to hoist!
BEN: 好的! 已经准备好举起来了!
LON: Two on each side: Ready now? Push!
LON: 每边各两个人 准备好了吗? 推!
Watch it! lt's slipping,
看这边! 滑掉了
Come on, lads, it's only a little picket fence,
加油啊, 伙计们 这只是一块篱笆
-Steady! Steady! -Thene you go:
-稳住! 稳住! -这就行了
That'll keep everything out, eh, John?
这会把一切挡在外面, 恩, John?
Something wrong, John?
有什么不妥吗, John?
What?
什么?
You've been awfully quiet the last few days,
这几天你都异常地平静
Oh, he's just mad that he missed all the action,
哦, 他只是觉得 他失去了所有的作用
Ah, don't worry, John,
啊, 不用着急, John
You'll get your chance to deal with the lndians,
你会有机会去对付 那些印第安人的
Yeah, We'll take care of them,,,
对 我们会好好照顾他们的...
like we did last time, eh, mates?
就像上次那样 恩, 大伙?
We shot ourselves an injun
我们会为自己 打死一个印第安人
On maybe two on thnee
或许两个三个
All right, you howling nutter, get to work,
好了, 你个疯子 快去做事
Come on, Ben, lt's just a little fun,
不要这样, Ben 只是开开玩笑而已
Oh, sure! We're having loads of fun, right?
哦, 当然! 我们有很多乐趣, 不是吗?
Look at us-- no gold, no food,,,
看看我们-- 没有金子, 没有食物...
while Ratcliffe sits up in his tent all day,,,
那个Ratcliffe还整天 坐在他的帐篷里...
happy as a clam,
快活得像个蛤蛎
l'm doomed!
我的天啊!
l should be wallowing in riches by now,,,
现在我已经应该在金子里打滚了...
and l haven't found as much as a speck,
而我却还没有找到一点点金疙瘩
Think: Think!
想想, 想想!
It's got to be around hene somewhene:
应该就在这附近的某个地方
W hoeree coulcd t boe?
到底应该在哪儿呢?
[Playing ''London Bridge ls Falling Down'']
[演奏 ''London Bridge ls Falling Down'']
I've mined the forests and the hills:::
我已经挖掘过森林和山丘
and the swamps:::and nothing!
还有沼泽...什么都没有!
Grr!
咯噜噜!
[Yipping]
[汪汪汪]
Why can't l find it? What am l overlooking?
为什么我找不到? 我到底忽略了哪里?
-WIGGINS: Aah! -Oh!
-WIGGINS: 啊! -哦!
l--l--
我--我--
l made it myself!
我自己做的!
Take that silly--
那样看起来很傻--
Of course, The lndians,
肯定是的, 那些印第安人
Wiggins, why do you think,,,
Wiggins, 你觉得为什么...
those insolent heathens attacked us?
那些野蛮人要袭击我们?
Because we invaded their land,,,
因为我们侵入了他们的地盘
and cut down their trees and dug up their earth?
砍了他们的树挖了他们的土地?
lt's the gold! They have it,,,
是金子! 他们拥有金子...
and they don't want us to take it from them,
他们不愿意我们把它带走
l'll just have to take it by force then, won't l?
那么我就只好用武力了, 不是吗?
You there! Where's Captain Smith?
你们这些人! Smith船长去哪儿了?
Well, he's,,,gone,
恩, 他...不在了
Aye, Your singing must've scared him off,
对, 一定是你唱歌把他吓跑了
Then go get him, for heaven's sake!
那么以上天的旨意把他找回来!
What if we run into the lndians?
要是我们走进 印第安人领域怎么办?
That's what guns are for,
那就用枪来对付他们
Now arm yourselves and get moving!
马上武装起来出发!
[Percy howls]
[Percy怒吼]
[Yipping]
[汪汪汪]
[Chitters]
[啾啾声]
[Groans]
[呻吟声]
[Squeaking]
[啸叫]
[Sighs]
[叹息声]
POWHATAN: Pocahontas:
POWHATAN: Pocahontas
You should be inside the village,
你应该待在部落里
We'll be all right,
我们会没事的
We're gathering food for when the warriors arrive,
我们正在为战士们准备食物
Don't go far,
不要走太远了
Now is not the time to be running off,
现在不是到处乱跑的时候
Yes, Father,
是的, 父亲
When l see you wear that necklace,,,
当我看到你戴着那串项链...
you look just like your mother,
感觉你就像你母亲一样
l miss her,
我想她
But she is still with us,
但她仍然和我们在一起
Whenever the wind moves through the trees,,,
无论何时风吹过树林...
l feel her presence,
我就感觉到她的存在
Our people look to her for wisdom and strength,
我们的人民向她祈祷智慧和力量
Someday, they will look to you as well,
有一天 他们也会向你祈祷
l would be honored by that,
我会感到无限荣耀
You shouldn't be out here alone,
你不应该单独待在这儿
l'll send for Kocoum,
我会叫Kocoum过来的
All right, what is it?
够了, 那是什么?
-What? -You're hiding something,
-什么? -你隐瞒着什么东西
l'm not hiding anything,
我没有隐瞒任何东西
Pocahontas, you can tell me, l promise,
Pocahontas, 你可以告诉我 我发誓
l won't tell anyone-- Pocahontas, look!
我不会告诉任何人的-- Pocahontas, 看!
[Squeaks]
[尖叫声]
lt's one of them! l'm going to get--
这是他们其中一个! 我要去找--
What are you doing here?
你在这儿干什么?
l had to see you again,
我必须要再见你一次
-Pocahontas! -Oh!
-Pocahontas! -哦!
Pocahontas!
Pocahontas!
Please! Don't say anything,
求你! 不要说任何东西
Quick! This way!
快! 这边!
-But-- -Nakoma,
-但是-- -Nakoma
Where is Pocahontas?
Pocahontas呢?
l--l haven't seen her,
我--我没有看到她
[Sighs] Pocahontas can't keep running off,
[叹气] Pocahontas 不能再到处乱跑了
lt's dangerous out there,
在外面很危险
Tell her that, She listens to you,
告诉她这些 她听你的话
Heh! Sure she does,
嗨! 她当然会
JOHN: This place is incnedible:
JOHN: 这个地方实在太难以置信了
And to think we came all this way,,,
想想我们一路上来...
just to dig it up for gold,
只是去到处挖金子
POCAHONTAS: Gold?
POCAHONTAS: 金子?
-Hey, Meeko, -What's gold?
-嗨, Meeko, -什么是金子?
You know, it's yellow,
你也许知道, 黄黄的
lt comes out of the ground, lt's really valuable,
从地里头来的 非常宝贵
Oh! Here, we have lots of it,
哦! 这个, 我们这儿有很多
Gold,
金子
No, no! Gold is this,
不, 不! 金子是这个
Hmm, There's nothing like that around here,
, 这附近没有这样的东西
-No gold? -Not that l've seen,
-没有金子? -至少我没见过
Heh heh! All this way for nothing,
嗨嗨! 这一趟算是白跑了
Those boys are in for a big surprise,
那些孩子们将会大吃一惊的
-Will they leave? -Some of them might,
-他们会离开吗? -其中一些可能会
Will you go home?
你会回家吗?
lt's not like l have much of a home to go back to,
我看起来不像那种 有一个家可回的人
l've never really belonged anywhere,
我从来没有 真正属于过任何地方
You could belong here,
你可以属于这儿
[Voice singing on the wind]
[风中声音歌唱]
What was that?!
那是什么?!
Did you see something?
你看到什么了吗?
No, No, l just--l--
不, 不, 我只是--我--
l didn't see anything, Did l?
我没有看到任何东西 是不是?
Look again,
再看一次
Let it bneak upon you
让它来指引你
Like a wave upon the sand
就像波浪打在沙滩上
Hello, John Smith,
你好, John Smith
Pocahontas, that tree is talking to me,
Pocahontas 那棵树在和我说话
Then you should talk back,
那么你就应该回答
Don't be fnightened, young man:
不要害怕 年轻人
My bark is worse than my bite,
我的树皮比我的咬更糟糕
Say something,
说点什么
What do you say to a tree?
对一棵树应该说些什么?
Anything you want,
任何你想说的
So, uh,,,
那么, 恩...
Come closer, John Smith,
靠近些, John Smith
He has a good soul,
他有一个善良的灵魂
And he's handsome, too!
他也很帅气!
-Oh, l like her, -l knew you would,
-哦, 我喜欢她 -我知道你会的
BEN: Smith!
BEN: Smith!
Smith, where are you, mate?
Smith, 你在哪儿, 伙计?
We can't let them see us,
我们不能让他们看见
Quick! Over here,
快! 到那边去
This place gives me the creeps,
这个地方让我害怕
Savages could be hiding anywhere,
野蛮人可能躲在任何地方
Aye, if you spot one, don't ask questions, Just shoot,
对, 如果你发现一个 不要多想, 尽管开枪就是
-Whoa! -Oh!
-呼啊! -哦!
Watch your feet, you big oaf!
看看你的脚, 你个畸形儿!
lt wasn't me! lt was the tree,
不是我! 是这棵树
Oh, of course!
哦, 当然!
The tree just felt like lifting its roots--
这棵树好像把它的根抬了一下--
Let's get out of here,
让我们赶快离开这儿
-Ow! Run! -Ow!
-啊哦! 快跑啊! -啊哦!
But what about Smith?
但是Smith怎么办?
He's a big lad! He can take care of himself!
他已经是个大人了! 他能够照顾自己的!
l'm glad you're on our side,
我真高兴你们能站在我这边
There's still some snap in these old vines,
这些古老的藤蔓 倒是还有些力气
l better get back before they send the whole camp after me,
我最好在他们把所有人 都派来找我之前赶回去
When will l see you again?
我们什么时候能再见面?
Meet me tonight, right here,
今天晚上, 就在这儿
Well! l haven't had this much excitement in 200 years,
恩哈! 我已经200年 没有碰到这种兴奋的事了
What am l doing? l shouldn't be seeing him again,
我到底在做什么? 我不应该再去见他了
l mean, l want to see him again,
我的意思是 我还想再见到他
Who wouldn't?
谁不想? 我也想再见到他
But still, something inside,,,
但是仍然, 一种内在的感觉...
is telling me it's the right thing,
在告诉我 这是对的
Perhaps it's your dream,
或许这就是你的梦
My dream? Do you think he's the one,,,
我的梦? 你是说他就是...
the spinning arrow was pointing to?
那个旋转的箭头所指向的?
Hmm!
!
The warriors are here!
战士们来了!
[Crowd shouting]
[人群喧嚣声]
Pocahontas, are you crazy? What were you doing?
Pocahontas, 你疯了吗? 你到底在做什么?
-There you are! -Kocoum!
-你在这儿! -Kocoum!
Look at them! Now we have enough warriors,,,
看看他们! 现在我们有足够的勇士...
to destroy those white demons!
去摧毁那些白皮肤的魔鬼!
Now that we are joined by our brothers,,,
既然我们的兄弟们加入了...
we will defeat this enemy,
我们就要去击败那些敌人
Father, l need to speak with you,
父亲 我想和你谈谈
Not now, my daughter, The council is gathering,
现在不行, 我的女儿 首领们正在商量事情
We don't have to fight them, There must be a better way,
我们并不需要和他们打仗 一定有一条更好的路可走
Sometimes our paths are chosen for us,
有时候我们的路是已经定了的
But maybe we should try talking to them,
但是也许我们 可以试着和他们谈谈
They do not want to talk,
他们并不想谈判
But if one of them did want to talk,,,
但是如果他们 其中一个真的想要呢...
you would listen to him, wouldn't you?
你会听他的 是吗?
-Pocahontas-- -Wouldn't you?
-Pocahontas-- -是吗?
Of course l would, but it is not that simple,
当然我会 但是事情并不是那么简单
Nothing is simple anymore,
没有事情会很简单的
[Twig snaps] Uh-oh!
[树枝折断] 恩-哦!
Huh?! [Barks]
哼?! [汪汪汪]
[Growling]
[低声咆哮]
[Chitters]
[啾啾声]
Oof!
哦呋!
[Howls]
[嚎叫]
Easy, Thomas, it's me,
别紧张, Thomas, 是我
Oh, John! l could've killed you,
哦, John! 我差点打中你
Not aiming like that, you couldn't,
不是这样瞄准的 你打不中
Keep both eyes open when you shoot,
当你射击的时候 两只眼睛都睁着
You'll see twice as well,
你会看到两倍的东西
Smith! There you are!
Smith! 你回来了!
We were looking all over for you,
我们正四处找你
Smith! Where have you been?
Smith! 你刚刚去哪儿了?
l was out scouting the terrain, sir,
我去观察地形了, 长官
Excellent, Then you must know the lndians' whereabouts,
聪明, 那么你一定 知道印第安人的行踪了
We'll need that information for the battle,
这些信息对我们的 战役应该会有帮助的
What battle?
什么战役?
We will eliminate these savages once and for all,
我们要把这些 野蛮人一次消灭干净
No! You can't do that!
不! 你不能那么做!
Oh, can't l?
哦, 不能?
Look, we don't have to fight them,
你看, 我们 并不需要和他们打仗
-John, what's gotten into you? -l met one of them,
-John, 你怎么了? -我见过他们当中一个
-You what?! -A savage?
-你什么?! -一个野蛮人?
They're not savages, They can help us,
他们不是野蛮人 他们能够帮助我们
They know the land,
他们了解这片土地
They know how to navigate the rivers,
他们知道怎样在河里航行
[Trills]
[颤音]
-And look, lt's food, -What is it?
-再看, 这是食物 -这是什么?
lt's better than hardtack and gruel, that's for sure,
这个肯定比硬面饼和稀粥强
l like gruel,
我喜欢稀粥
They don't want to feed us, you ninnies!
他们不会给我们食物 你们这些笨蛋!
They want to kill us! All of us!
他们想要杀死我们! 我们所有的人!
They've got our gold,,,
他们拿走了我们的金子...
and they'll do anything to keep it!
为了留住它 他们会做出任何事情!
But there is no gold,
但是这儿没有金子
No gold?
没有金子?
And l suppose your little lndian friend told you this?
我猜肯定是你的 印第安小朋友告诉你的?
Yes,
没错
Lies! Lies! All of it! Murderous thieves,
谎言! 谎言! 一切都是谎言! 危险的小偷
There's no room for their kind in civilized society,
在文明世界中他们没有立足之地
But this is their land!
但是这儿是他们的地盘!
This is my land! l make the laws here,
这是我的地盘! 我在这儿制定法律
And l say anyone who so much as looks at an lndian,,,
我说过任何人这样亲近地 见过一个印第安人...
without killing him on sight,,,
而没有将他在眼前杀死...
will be tried for treason and hanged,
将被判为叛国罪而处以绞刑
[Coyote howls]
[狼嚎声]
Pocahontas!
Pocahontas!
-Nakoma, -Don't go out there,
-Nakoma -不要去那儿了
l lied for you once, Don't ask me to do it again,
我为你撒过一次谎 不要让我再做一次
l have to do this,
我必须要这样做
-He's one of them! -You don't know him,
-他是他们其中之一! -你不了解他
lf you go out there,,,
如果你去了那儿...
you'll be turning your back on your own people,
你就会背叛你自己的族人
l'm trying to help my people,
我在努力拯救我的族人
Pocahontas, please, You're my best friend,
Pocahontas, 求你 你是我最好的朋友
l don't want you to get hurt,
我不想看到你受到伤害
l won't, l know what l'm doing,
我不会的 我知道我自己在做什么
Pocahontas, no!
Pocahontas, 不!
BEN: Ratcliffe wouldn't take us:::
BEN: Ratcliffe不会让我们...
halfway around the World for nothing:
在这个世界什么都找不到
LON: But what if Smith is night?
LON: 但是如果 Smith说得是真的呢?
W hat fthoeree s no golcd?
如果真的没有金子该怎么办?
MAN: lf you ask me,,,
MAN: 如果你问我...
Ratcliffe's been lying to us since we left London,
Ratcliffe从我们离开 伦敦的时候就在骗我们
Listen to you, you bunch of idiots,
听着 你们这些白痴
Those savages didn't attack us for nothing,
那些野蛮人不会 吃了没事和我们打战的
They're hiding something,
他们一定在隐藏着什么东西
LON: If they do have the gold:::
LON: 如果他们真的有金子...
I neckon we'll have to fight them:
我想我们会和他们打战的
Either too hot or too cold,
要不太冷要不太热
I haven't been comfortable since we got hene:
我从一到这儿就没舒服过
GU ARD: Me, too: I'm itching a lot:
守卫: 我也是 我痒得难受
[Gasps]
[吸气声]
-Follow him, -Yes, Governor,
-跟着他 -是的, 长官
l want to know where he's sneaking off to,
我想知道他偷偷地跑去哪儿
Yes, sir,
是的, 长官
And if you happen to see any lndians,,,
如果你碰巧遇到什么印第安人
shoot them,
开枪打死他
Oh, Thomas, you've been a slipshod sailor,,,
哦, Thomas 你已经是一个差劲的水手...
and a poor excuse for a soldier,
又是一个可怜的士兵
Don't disappoint me again,
不要让我再次失望
-Kocoum, -What is it?
-Kocoum -什么事?
lt's Pocahontas,
是关于Pocahontas的
What's wrong? ls she all right?
怎么了? 她还好吗?
l think she's in trouble,
我想她有麻烦了
The earth is trembling, child, What's happened?
大地在颤抖, 孩子 发生什么事了?
The warriors are here,
战士们在这儿
-Pocahontas, -John!
-Pocahontas -John!
Listen to me,
听我说
My men are planning to attack your people,
我们的人正在计划攻击你的族人
You've got to warn them,
你得去通知他们
Maybe it's not too late to stop this,
也许太晚了
You have to come with me and talk to my father,
你得跟我一起回去 去和我父亲谈判
Pocahontas, talking isn't going to do any good,
Pocahontas 谈判已经没有用了
l've already tried talking to my men,,,
我已经努力地 去和我们的人谈了...
but everything about this land has them spooked,
但是这片土地上的任何 一件事情都让他们感到恐惧
[Distorted howling]
[扭曲的嚎叫声]
That's the strangest creature l've ever seen!
那是我见过的最奇怪的生物!
[Yipping and yelping]
[汪汪汪汪汪]
Percy?!
Percy?!
Easy, Percy! Come here!
放松点, Percy! 到这儿来!
Meeko, come back!
Meeko, 回来!
You see what l mean?
你看这就是我的意思?
Once two sides want to fight, nothing can stop them,
一旦双方准备开仗 谁也挡不住
Come here both of you!
你们俩都给我过来!
lt's all right, He's a friend,
好了好了 他是一个朋友
Bad! Bad dog! Sit!
坏! 坏狗! 坐下!
[Laughs]
[笑声]
-What ane you doing? Meeko! -Pency, get back hene!
-你在干什么? Meeko! -Pency, 回到这里来!
What ane you doing? Stop that!
你在干什么? 停下来!
All right, that's enough!
好了, 够了!
[Yelps]
[汪]
It's enough to make your sap boil:
足够让你的体液沸腾
Now then, there's something l want to show you, Look!
现在, 我有样东西给你们看, 看!
The ripples,
这些波纹
What about them?
他们什么意思?
GRANDMO THER WILLOW: So small at finst:::
WILLOW奶奶: 一开始很小...
then look how they grow:
然后看他们扩散得多大
But someone has to start them,
但是总得有人去开始
They're not going to listen to us,
他们不会听我们的
Young man, sometimes the right path,,,
年轻人 有时候正确的路
is not the easiest one,
往往不是最简单的那条
Don't you see? Only when the fighting stops:::
难道你不明白? 只有当战争停止了...
can you be togethen:
你们才能在一起
All right, Let's go talk to your father,
好吧 让我们去和你父亲谈判
[Chirps]
[叽叽喳喳声]
[Squeaks]
[尖叫声]
[Breathing heavily]
[气急败坏]
[Shouts battle cry]
[狂喊]
[Gasps]
[吸气声]
Kocoum, no!
Kocoum, 不!
Kocoum!
Kocoum!
Leave him alone! Unh! Unh! Unh!
放开他! 恩! 恩! 恩!
Grr!
呃!
Unh!
恩!
Kocoum, stop!
Kocoum, 停下来!
Both eyes open,
双眼睁开
Unh,
恩
[Gasps]
[吸气声]
-Thomas! -ls he--
-Thomas! -他--
You killed him,
你杀了他
-l thought that-- -Get away from him!
-我以为-- -离他远些!
Pocahontas, it won't help! He was only--
Pocahontas, 这样没有用的! 他只是--
He killed him!
他杀了他!
[Warriors shouting in distance]
[远处战士叫声]
Thomas, get out of here!
Thomas, 离开这儿!
Get out of here!
离开这儿!
[Warriors shouting]
[战士叫声]
[Grunting]
[咕哝声]
[Whispering in Algonquian]
[用阿尔冈琴语低声说]
[Percy whimpering]
[Percy呜咽]
[Whimpers]
[呜咽]
[Trills]
[颤声]
[Men muttering, woman sobbing]
[男声咕哝, 女声呜咽]
Who did this?
谁干的?
Pocahontas was out in the woods,
Pocahontas在野外树林里
Kocoum went to find her and this white man attacked them,
Kocoum去找他 这个白人袭击了他们
Your weapons are strong,,,
你们的武器很厉害
but now our anger is stronger,
但是现在我的怒火更厉害
At sunrise, he will be the first to die!
在太阳升起的时候 就将他首先处死!
But, Father!
但是, 父亲!
l told you to stay in the village,
我告诉过你待在部落里
You disobeyed me,
你违背了我
You have shamed your father!
你让你的父亲蒙羞!
l was only trying to help,
我只是想做点帮助
Because of your foolishness, Kocoum is dead!
就因为你的愚蠢 Kocoum死掉了!
Take him away!
把他带走!
Kocoum was just coming to protect me,
Kocoum只是想来保护我
Pocahontas,,,
Pocahontas...
l sent Kocoum after you,
是我让Kocoum跟着你的
l was worried about you,
我很担心你
l thought l was doing the right thing,
我原以为我做了件正确的事
All this happened because of me,
所有这些都是因我而起
And now l'll never see John Smith again,
现在我再也 见不到John Smith了
Come with me,
跟我来
Pocahontas wants to look into the eyes,,,
Pocahontas想最后看一眼...
of the man who killed Kocoum,
那个杀了Kocoum的人
Be quick,
最好快点
Pocahontas,
Pocahontas
l'm so sorry,
我真是抱歉
For what? This?
为了什么? 这件事吗?
l've gotten out of worse scrapes than this,
比这还糟糕的困境 我都摆脱出来了
Can't think of any right now, but--
现在什么都不想, 但是--
lt would've been better if we'd never met,
如果我们不曾见过 事情也许不会这么糟糕
None of this would've happened,
这些事情都不会发生
Pocahontas, look at me,
Pocahontas, 看着我
l'd rather die tomorrow,,,
我情愿明天就去死...
than live a hundred years without knowing you,
也不要不认识而活了一百年
If I never knew you
如果我不曾认识你
If I never felt this love
如果我没有感到这份爱
I would have no inkling of
我将不会知道
How pnecious life can be
生命原来可以这么珍贵
If I never held you
如果我不曾扶过你
I would never have a clue
我也不会知道
How at last I'd find in you
我到底在你身上找到什么
The missing pant of me
我所没有的部分
In this World so full of fean
在这个世界上 充满了害怕
Full of nage and lies
充满了愤怒与谎言
I can see the tnuth so clean
我能够如此清晰地看到真情
In your eyes
就在你的眼中
So dny your eyes
所以擦干你的眼泪
And I'm so gnateful to you
我对你如此地感激
I'd have lived my whole life through
我将会在失落中
Lost foreven
度过一生
If I never knew you
如果我不曾认识你
I thought our love would be so beautiful
我想我们的爱会如此美丽
Somehow we'd make
不知如何我们让
The whole World bnight
整个世界充满光明
I never knew that fean and hate
我从来不知道害怕和憎恨
Could be so stnong
会如此强烈
All they'd leave us wene these whispens
它们所留给我的一切 就是这些私语
In the night
回荡在今夜
But still my heant is saying we wene night
但是我的心 一直在说这是对的
for if I never knew you
如果我不曾认识你
JOHN: Thene's no moment I negnet
JOHN: 我不会花时间来后悔
POCAHONTAS: If I never knew this love
POCAHONTAS: 如果我不曾感到这份爱
JOHN:  Since the moment that we met
JOHN: 自从我们见面的那一刻
POCAHONTAS: I would have no inkling of
POCAHONTAS: 我将不会知道
JOHN:  If our time has gone too fast
JOHN: 如果我们的时间去得太快
POCAHONTAS: How pnecious life can be
POCAHONTAS: 生命原来可以这么珍贵
JOHN:  I've lived at last
JOHN: 我已经到了生命的最后一刻
Pocahontas,
Pocahontas
l can't leave you,
我不能离开你
You never will,
你永远不会
No matter what happens to me,,,
无论我发生了什么...
l'll always be with you, Forever,
我都会和你在一起 直到永久
And I'm so gnateful to you
我对你如此地感激
I'd have lived my whole life through
我在这个世界上活得
Empty as the sky
如此空荡荡就像天空
Never knowing why
从来不知道为什么
Lost foreven
失去永久
If I never knew you
如果我不曾认识你
THOMAS: Help! Somebody help!
THOMAS: 救命! 谁来救命!
Help! Help!
救命! 救命!
Easy, lad, What is it?
别紧张, 小子, 怎么了?
lt's Smith! They got him!
是Smith! 他们抓住了他!
-Who got him? -The savages!
-谁抓住他了? -那些野蛮人!
They captured him, dragged him off!
他们抓住他 把他拖走了!
-Where'd they take him? -They headed north,
-他们把他带到哪里去了? -他们向北面去了
-How many wene thene? -At least a dozen:
-他们有多少人? -至少一打
BEN: Filthy beasts!
BEN: 肮脏的畜生!
-Oof! -lt's perfect, Wiggins!
-哦呋! -太好了, Wiggins!
l couldn't have planned this better myself,
没有比我的计划更好的了
The gold is as good as mine,
那些金子就是我的啦
We've got to save him! He'd do the same for any of us,
我们必须去救他! 他夜曾经救过我们
Thomas is right! We've got to do something,
Thomas说得没错! 我们必须要做些事情了
RATCLIFFE: And so we shall:
RATCLIFFE: 还有我们也会的
l told you those savages couldn't be trusted,
我告诉过你们那些 野蛮人是不能被信任的
Smith tried to befriend them,,,
Smith努力地去和他们交朋友
and look what they've done to him!
看看他们对他做了什么!
But now l say it's time to rescue our courageous comrade,
现在是我们去营救我们 勇敢的同志的时候了
At daybreak, we attack!
天亮我们就出击!
[Men cheering]
[欢呼声]
What can you expect fnom filthy little heathens?
你们能对肮脏的 小野蛮期待什么?
Hene's what you get when naces ane divense
这就是你们所得到的 当种族不同的时候
Thein skin's a hellish ned
他们的皮肤是地狱般的红色
They'ne only good when dead
他们只有死的时候才最乖
They'ne venmin as I said and wonse
他们是害虫 就像我所说的甚至更糟
They'ne savages, savages
他们是野蛮人, 野蛮人
Banely even human
几乎不是人类
Savages, savages
野蛮人, 野蛮人
Dnive them fnom our shone!
把他们赶出我们的海岸!
They'ne not like you and me
他们不像你和我
Which means they must be evil
他们是恶魔
We must sound the dnums of wan
我们要敲响战鼓
They'ne savages, savages
他们是野蛮人, 野蛮人
Dinty shnieking devils
肮脏尖叫着的魔鬼
Now we sound the dnums of wan
现在我们敲响战鼓
This is what we feaned
这是一场我们害怕的战争
The paleface is a demon
那些白脸的都是魔鬼
The only thing they feel at all is gneed
他们仅有的感觉是贪婪
Beneath that milky hide
在那乳白色的皮肤之下
Thene's emptiness inside
里面全都是空的
I wonden if they even bleed
我奇怪他们甚至流血
They'ne savages, savages
他们是野蛮人, 野蛮人
Banely even human
几乎不是人类
Savages, savages
野蛮人, 野蛮人
Killens at the cone
本质上是凶手
They'ne diffenent fnom us
他们和我们不一样
Which means they can't be tnusted
他们能不能被信任
We must sound the dnums of wan
我们要敲响战鼓
They'ne savages, savages
他们是野蛮人, 野蛮人
Finst we deal with this one
首先让我们来处理这个
Then we sound the dnums of wan
然后我们敲响战鼓
Savages, savages
野蛮人, 野蛮人
Let's go get a few, men!
让我们去杀掉几个, 伙计们!
Now it's up to you, men
现在就靠你们了, 大家
Savages, savages
野蛮人, 野蛮人
Banely even human
几乎不是人类
Now we sound the dnums
现在我们敲响...
Of wan
战鼓
They're going to kill him at sunrise, Grandmother Willow,
他们准备在太阳升起 的时候处决他, Willow奶奶
You have to stop them,
你得去制止他们
-l can't, -Child, remember your dream,
-我没有办法 -孩子, 记住你那个梦
l was wrong, Grandmother Willow,
我错了, Willow奶奶
l followed the wrong path,
我走错了一条路
l feel so lost,
我感到很失落
Huh? Ah!
哼? 啊!
[Whines]
[呜呜声]
[Chirps]
[唧唧喳喳声]
The compass,
指南针
The spinning arrow,
旋转的指针
lt's the arrow from your dream!
这是你梦里的指针!
l was right! lt was pointing to him!
我是对的! 它正指向他!
[Gentle winds blowing]
[微风拂过]
Sunrise!
日出!
lt's not too late, child!
还不晚, 孩子!
Let the spirits of the earth guide you!
让大地的灵魂来指引你!
You know your path, child: Now follow it!
你知道你的路, 孩子 现在跟随着它!
[Drums beating]
[战鼓声]
This will be the day
就是这一天
Let's go, men!
让我们出发, 大家!
This will be the monning
早上即将来临
Bring out the prisoner!
把那个囚犯带出来!
MEN:  We will see them dying in the dust
大家: 我们要看着 他们垂死在烟尘中
I don't know what I can do
我不知道我能做什么
Still I know I've got to tny
我只知道我必须去争取
Now we make them pay
现在就要让他们付出代价
Eagle, help my feet to fly
鹰啊, 帮我飞起来吧
Now, without a wanning
现在, 没有警告
Mountain, help my heant be gneat
大山 让我的心灵变得伟大
Now we leave them blood and bone and nust
我们留给他们血骨和锈迹
Spinits of the earth and sky
大地和天空的灵魂
It's them on us
要么他们, 要么我们
Please don't let it be too late
请不要让我太晚了
They'ne just a bunch of filthy, stinking savages
他们只是一群肮脏 烂臭的野蛮人
-Savages! -Demons!
-野蛮人! -魔鬼!
-Devils! -Kill them!
-恶魔! -杀死他们!
Savages, savages
野蛮人, 野蛮人
What are we waiting for?
我们还等什么?
ALL:  Destnoy thein evil nace
所有人:  摧毁 他们邪恶的种族
Until thene's not a tnace left
直到没有任何痕迹留下
How loud ane the dnums of wan?
多么嘹亮的战鼓!
Now we see what comes of tnying to be chums
现在我们看到了试图交好的下场
Is the death of all I love
是我所爱的一切的死去
Cannied in the dnumming of
继续擂动...
- Wan -No!
- 战鼓 - 不!
lf you kill him, you'll have to kill me too,
如果你要杀死他 你就先杀了我
Daughter, stand back,
女儿, 让开
l won't! l love him, Father,
我不! 我爱他, 父亲
Look arourd you,
看看你的四周
This is where the path of hatred has brought us,
这就是你的仇恨之路 给我们带来的
This is the path l choose, Father,
这是我选择的路 父亲
What will yours be?
想想你的那条将会是怎样?
[Gentle winds blowing]
[微风拂过]
My daughter speaks with a wisdom beyond her years,
我女儿的话蕴涵了 一种超乎她的年龄的智慧
We have all come here with anger in our hearts,,,
我们都是带着 一颗愤怒的心来的...
but she comes with courage and understanding,
但是她是带着 勇气和理解来的
From this day forward,,,
从今天开始...
if there is to be more killing,,,
如果再会有杀戮的话...
it will not start with me,
那绝对不会是我发起的
Release him,
释放他
Now is our chance! Fire!
这正是一个好机会! 开火!
-No, -What?
-不 -什么?
-They let him go! -They don't want to fight!
-他们释放了他! -他们并不想打仗!
lt's a trick, don't you see? Fire!
这是个骗局 你们还不明白吗? 开火!
Fine! l'll settle this myself,
开火! 我自己来解决
JOHN: No!
JOHN: 不!
John!
John!
You shot him!
你打中了他!
He stepped right into it!
是他自己扑上去的!
lt's his own fault!
这是他自己的错!
BEN: Smith was night all along:
BEN: Smith一直都是对的
LON: We never should've listened to you:
LON: 我们真不应该 听了你的话
-Get the gun! -Traitors!
-把他的枪抢过来! -叛徒!
Unhand me! l say, how dare you!
放开我! 我说, 你们怎么敢这样!
Put him in chains!
用镣铐把他锁起来!
l'll see you all hanged for this!
我会看到你因为这件事被绞死的!
And gag him as well!
把他的嘴也堵起来!
RATCLIFFE: Uhh!
RATCLIFFE: 啊!
[Seagulls cawing]
[海鸥叫声]
ls he going to make it, Thomas?
他能够挺过去吗, Thomas?
The sooner he gets back to England, the better,
最好尽快把他送回伦敦
Let's hope the wind is with him,
希望他一帆风顺
ls the ship ready yet?
船准备好了吗?
Any minute now,
任何时候都可以出发
Just loading the last bit of cargo,
只是在装载最后一批货物
[Grunts]
[咕哝]
[Muffled] How dare you! Untie me at once!
[被蒙住的] 你们怎么敢这样! 立刻放开我!
l'll have your head for this!
我会要了你们的脑袋!
[Sniffles] And he came so highly recommended,
[抽鼻涕] 他总是 把自己想得太高了
[Sighs]
[叹气]
The ship's almost ready,
船已经准备好了
We'd better get you on board, We'll lose the tide,
我们最好把你抬到甲板上 我们会错过潮汐的
No, not yet, She said she'd be here,
不, 先不要 她说了她会来的
Look,
看
Going back is his only chance,
回去是他生存下去的唯一希望
He'll die if he stays here,
如果待在这儿 他会死的
Here,
这
lt's from Grandmother Willow's bark,
是来自Willow奶奶的树皮
lt'll help with the pain,
它可以止痛
What pain?
什么痛?
l've had worse pain than this, [Grunts]
比这个更严重的伤我都有过 [咕哝]
Can't think of any right now, but,,,
一时间想不到那么多, 但是...
You are always welcome among our people,
你在我们的族人中 永远都是受欢迎的
Thank you, my brother,
谢谢, 亲爱的兄弟
l thought you didn't like strangers,
我原以为你不喜欢陌生人
[Chirps]
[叽叽声]
Err! Gehh!
喏! 嘎!
Err!
喏!
My mother's necklace,
母亲的项链
JOHN: See ya, Pency:
JOHN: 再见, Pency
[Sneezes]
[打喷嚏]
[Chirps]
[叽叽声]
Come with me?
和我一起走吧?
You must choose your own path,
你必须选择你自己的路
l'm needed here,
我离不开这儿
Then,,,l'll stay with you,
那么...我留下来陪你
No, You have to go back,
不, 你必须回去
-But l can't leave you, -You never will,
-但是我离不开你 -你永远不会离开我
No matter what happens, l'll always be with you,,,
不论发生什么事 我会一直和你在一起...
forever,
直到永久
And I'm so gnateful to you
我对你如此地感激
I'd have lived my whole life through
我度过我的一生在...
-Good luck, lad, -Godspeed, John,
-祝你好运, 伙计 -一路平安, John
[lndistinct shouting]
[模糊的喊声]
MAN: Raise anchon!
大家: 起锚!
[Bell clanging]
[铃声叮当]
[Panting]
[喘气]
[Winds blowing]
[微风拂过]
[''lf l Never Knew You'' begins]
[''lf l Never Knew You'' 开始]
If I never knew you
如果我不曾认识你
If I never felt this love
如果我没有感到这份爱
I would have no inkling of how pnecious life can be
我将不会知道 生命原来可以这么珍贵
And I'm so gnateful to you
我对你如此地感激
I'd have lived my whole life through
我将会在失落中
Lost foreven
度过一生
If I never knew you
如果我不曾认识你
I'd be safe but half as neal
我会很安全 但是真的不完整
Never knowing I could feel
从来不会感觉到
A love so stnong and tnue
爱会那么强烈那么真挚
Oh
哦
If I never knew you
如果我不曾认识你
Thene's no moment I negnet
我不会花时间来后悔
If I never knew your love
如果我不曾感到这份爱
Since the moment that we met
自从我们见面的那一刻
I would have no inkling of
我将不会知道
If our time has gone too fast
如果我们的时间去得太快
I've lived at last
我已经到了生命的最后一刻
Ahh
啊
Yeah, yeah
耶, 耶
I thought our love would be so beautiful
我想我们的爱会如此美丽
So beautiful
如此美丽
Somehow we'd make the whole World bnight
不知如何我们让 整个世界充满光明
I thought our love would be so beautiful
我想我们的爱会如此美丽
We'd tunn the dankness into light
我们将黑暗变成光明
And still my heant is saying we wene night
我的心仍然 一直在说这是对的
We wene night
这是对的
And if I never knew you
如果我不曾认识你
I'd have lived my whole life through
我在这个世界上活得
Empty as the sky
如此空荡荡就像天空
Never knowing why
从来不知道为什么
Lost foreven if I never knew you
失去永久 如果我不曾认识你
Yeah
耶
Ooh
哦
[''Colors of the Wind'' begins]
[''Colors of the Wind'' 开始]
You think you own whateven land you land on
你认为你所登陆的 土地都是你的
The earth is just a dead thing you can claim
大地只是一个没有生命的东西
But I know eveny nock and tnee and cneatune
但是我知道每一块石头 每一棵树木每一个生灵
Has a life, has a spinit, has a name
都有它的生命 有它的灵魂, 有它的名字
You think the only people who ane people
你认为只有像你那样
Ane the people who look and think like you
看问题和想问题的人 才是真正的人
But if you walk the footsteps of a stnangen
但是如果你沿着一个 陌生人的足迹走下去
You'll leann things you never knew you never knew
你会学到你从来不知道的事情 你从来不知道的事情
Have you even heand the wolf cny to the blue conn moon
你曾经听到过野狼嚎叫 对着蓝色天空里的明月
On let the eagle tell you whene he's been ?
或者问过野猫 为什么它要呲牙咆哮吗?
Can you sing with all the voices of the mourtain ?
你能和着大山的声音 一起唱歌吗?
Can you paint with all the colons of the wind?
你能用风的颜色 来绘画吗?
How high does the sycamone grow?
枫树 长得多么的高?
If you cut it down, then you'll never know
如果你把它砍了 你将永远不会知道
And you'll never hean the wolf cny
你将永远 不会听到野狼嚎叫
To the blue conn moon
对着蓝色天空里的明月
for whethen we ane white on coppen-skinned
不管我们是白色 还是棕色的皮肤
We need to sing with all the voices of the mountain
我们需要和着 大山的声音来歌唱
We need to paint with all the colons of the wind
我们需要用 风的颜色来绘画
You can own the earth and still
你会拥有大地 仍然
All you'll own is earth until
所有你将拥有的是大地直到
You can paint with all the colons of the wind
你能够用风的颜色来绘画